

Do Minh Son

Frontend Developer

Dob: 14/10/1998

Phone: 0352 326 767

Email: sondm1410@gmail.com

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/son-do-minh/

Address: Hanoi, Vietnam

OBJECTIVE

Short-term: Get a frontend developer job to advance my technical skills and gain experience.

Long-term: Learn more about both frontend and backend development, learn computer science, practice algorithms, so I can become a great software engineer. Connect with people in the industry.

EDUCATION

09/2016 - 09/2020

Bachelor's degree (not related to technology)

CyberSoft Programming Education Center
Programming foundation & Frontend development
Programming foundation: problem solving, Java language, OOP
Frontend: HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux

The Odin Project
Fullstack JavaScript
Web development and computer science basics, Git, GitHub, Linux commands
Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, responsive design

• Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, databases, template engines, API, authentication

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2020 - 12/2022 Officer in Hoa Binh province, Vietnam

01/3/2023 - 31/8/2023 FPT Software

Frontend Developer (ReactJS)

At FPT Software, I had the opportunity to work on CMP project (a multi-cloud management tool). My main contributions are:

- · Create VM screen
- · List screen and Details screen of Amazon S3 and Amazon RDS
- Change implementation: Config app routes and authorize users
- Other: write utilities, fix bugs, refactor code, improve UI

CERTIFICATIONS

09/2023 Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, CSS preprocessor (Sass), CSS framework (Bootstrap), Responsive Design

JavaScript, TypeScript	JavaScript core, DOM manipulation, form validation, network request, JavaScript libraries. Can work with TypeScript.
ReactJS	React fundamental, hooks, React Router, state management library (Redux, Redux Saga), UI library (Ant Design), Socket.io integration
Backend	NodeJS, Express, databases (MongoDB, SQL), template engines (Pug, EJS), REST API, authentication and authorization, Socket.io integration
Tools	Git, GitHub, Chrome Devtools, Visual Studio Code, Postman
English	TOEIC 825 in 2018; English Score 529 in 2023

REFERENCES

Mr. Pham Van Ky - Frontend Leader of CMP project at FPT Software - Phone: 0359.020.474

PROJECTS

Cloud Management Platform (CMP)

(01/3/2023 - 31/8/2023)

Name of customer	STE
Description	CMP is a multi-cloud management tool that allows you to enforce governance and security; visualize cost and usage patterns; manage cloud resources; optimize and implement service orchestration
Team size	12
My position	Frontend Developer (ReactJS)
My responsibility	Implement new features, build new screens, fix bugs, refactor code, make UI improvements
Technology	 Frontend: ReactJS, AngularJS, Redux, Redux Saga, Ant Design Backend: Spring Boot Database: PostgreSQL Service: AWS, Microsoft Azure, GCP

Real-time Tic-Tac-Toe

(10/2023 - 10/2023)

Description	Play tic-tac-toe with your friend on a 16 x 16 game board. Just create a room and send him/her the room ID to join (You can open the app in 2 parallel windows to test).
Link GitHub	https://github.com/SonDo580/tic-tac-toe
Link Website	https://sondm-tictactoe.netlify.app
My role	Fullstack Developer
My responsibility	Implement the game logic and display, handle client-server communication
Technology	ReactJS, NodeJS, Socket.io, TypeScript

Chess Rivals (in progress)

(11/2023 - now)

Description	Compete in a chess game
Link GitHub	https://github.com/SonDo580/chess-rivals

Link Website (beta)	https://sondm-chess.netlify.app
Features	 Implemented: board visualization, get valid moves, special moves (en passant, promotion, castling), check detection Todo: end game detection (checkmate, draw)
Technology	ReactJS, TypeScript To be added: NodeJS, Socket.io
Note	Currently doing everything on the Frontend

OTHER PROJECTS

My Portfolio

https://sondm-portfolio.netlify.app

© topcv.vn